nbtbank.com 2019-02-02

# NBT Bank | Privacy

## Personal Banking Privacy Notice for Consumer Customers

NBT Bank takes your privacy seriously and protects your personal information from unauthorized access and use. We use security measures that comply with federal law.

Read our Personal Banking Privacy Notice.

## Online Privacy Practices While Using Our Website

_Last updated: October 10, 2018_

At NBT Bank, your privacy counts to us. Our Online Privacy Practices explain how we collect, share, use, and protect information when you visit or use this website and/or any other online services offered by NBT Bank, non-banking affiliates and subsidiaries of NBT Bancorp Inc. that link to or reference these practices (collectively, our “online services”). This policy covers NBT Bank’s many online services, including NBT Bank websites, NBT Online Banker, NBT Bank Mobile Banking, NBT Bancorp Inc. subsidiary websites and official NBT Bank social media sites or pages, as well as any interactions you may have while viewing content provided through one of NBT Bank’s digital advertising campaigns.

### Our Online Privacy Practices follow these guiding principles: 

  * NBT Bank’s online services are intended for account holders and site visitors within the United States of America.
  * If you have a financial product or service with us, we will use and share any information that we collect from or about you in accordance with our Personal Banking Privacy Notice, which offers you certain choices with respect to the use and sharing of your personal information.

### Agreement with Practices

By using our website or other NBT Bank online services you are agreeing to our Online Privacy Practices and providing consent for our use and disclosure of information about you in the manner describe in these practices and in accordance with your Personal Banking Privacy Notice.

### Collection and Usage of Information

#### Collected Information

When you visit or use our online services, we may gather personal information from or about you to help improve how we serve you. This information could include information you provide to enroll or use a service such as your name, email address, mailing address, phone number(s), account numbers, user name and password. We may also collect debit or credit card information leveraged for payments, social security numbers, driver’s license numbers (or personal identification numbers) when you provide such information while using our online services and where we believe it is reasonably required for ordinary business purposes.

To monitor and support connectivity to our online services, we may also gather additional information about you such as your physical location, the type of device, browser and operating system you are using and your IP address and information about the site you came from, the parts of our online service you access, and the site you visit next. 

NBT Bank or our third-party partners may choose to use cookies, web beacons or other technologies to collect information and learn from your visit and/or use of our online services.  We may later couple the information we collect about you online with personal information about you.

We may also gather information about you from other online and offline sources including co-branded partner sites or commercially available third-party sources, such as credit reporting agencies.  We may combine this information with the personal and other information we have collected about you within our Online Privacy Practices.

#### Use of Information

The information described above may be used by NBT Bank in several ways to help us improve your experience using our online services and better serve your needs including, but not limited to:

  * Processing requested transactions, account actions or applications;
  * Positively confirming your personal identity;
  * Supporting fraud prevention and security measures;
  * Completing customer-initiated service and communication requests;
  * Analyzing use of our online services and the performance of those services, which may include your engagement and response to digital marketing campaigns; 
  * Delivering personalized information and marketing messages;
  * Improving the products, services and resources we provide to our customers and site visitors and the internal procedures and operations that support them;
  * Upholding all legal, industry-mandated and contractual requirements;

Anonymous data may also be collected for aggregation and support of business needs where permissible under applicable laws and regulation.

#### How We Collect Information

We, or our service providers, and other companies we work with may deploy and use cookies, web beacons, local shared objects and other tracking technologies for various purposes to support your engagement with us.

##### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device when you visit a website to help a provider, such as NBT Bank, track your activity and areas of interest. This information could be used to personalize or enhance your experience on the website or to inform you of relevant products, services or recommendations through other methods of outreach. Cookies can be used for helping continue an online session, fraud monitoring and information security protection practices.

Certain services or tools available through our online services may be provided and supported by a third-party, such as, but not limited to, social media platforms. These tools and resources may carry cookies utilized by the third-party. NBT encourages you to review privacy information on these third-party sites to learn more about how the data is used and managed.

Many web browsers do allow you to adjust your browser settings to deny or delete cookies, but doing so may negatively impact your experience using our online services. Your rejection of the use of cookies needs to be managed on each individual device and web browser you use.

##### Pixel Tags, Web Beacons and Clear GIFs

Pixel tags, web beacons and clear GIFs are very tiny transparent images located within a webpage or digital communications component that help us recognize a visitor or user and analyze your engagement with the platform or communication.

##### Flash Cookies or Local Shared Objects

Flash cookies or local shared objects can be stored on your device to help us support your return to our online services upon your next visit. These can be used to determine your browser type and Adobe® Flash® settings and how you are able to view content. 

Many of our online services include the use of advertisements. In these ads, we may discuss our own products or services or provide information about third-party services. The type of ad you see may be determined by the type of information we or our partners have about your online habits or banking relationship.

Online behavioral advertising refers to the collection of information from a computer or device regarding your web-browsing across non-affiliated websites over a period of time in order to deliver advertisements that may be of interest to you based on your browsing history and online activity.

##### IP Address

Your Internet Service Provider assigns your device a unique identification number known as your IP Address. This number is then logged by websites to identify you and your online activity and is a standard practice by many websites. This information can and may be used to monitor how frequently you visit a website, managing and troubleshooting connectivity issues, enhancing your site visitation experience through personalized or localized content, for security, advertising, site administration and other services.

### Disclosure of Information

When permissible under relevant laws and regulations, NBT Bank may share the information we collect about you with our third-party vendors, service providers and affiliates. Where appropriate, we will limit sharing of your information in accordance with our Personal Banking Privacy Notice. Examples of such sharing include, but may not be limited to:

  * NBT Bank affiliated websites and businesses in an effort to bring you improved products and services;
  * Other companies to bring you co-branded services, products or resources;  
  * Third parties or affiliates in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a sale, consolidation or merger of NBT Bank businesses; and
  * Other third parties to comply with legal requirements such as the demands of applicable subpoenas and court orders; to verify or enforce our terms of use, our other rights, or other applicable policies; to address fraud, security or technical issues; to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property or security of our customers or third parties; or
  * We may share anonymous or aggregated information with third parties to help deliver products, services, and content which are tailored to the users of our online services and for other purposes.

### Third-Party Websites

NBT Bank may provide links to websites that are owned or operated by other companies ("third-party websites") to help provide an expanded set of resources. If you choose to visit a third-party website referred to on our site, you will fall subject to the privacy and security practices of that site. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with those terms of use before providing information on that site.

### Online Privacy Protection for Children

NBT Bank’s online services are not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13). We strongly encourage that these individuals do not provide personal information through the website. NBT Bank does not knowingly collect information from children under 13 without parental consent.  More information regarding the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) can be obtained by visiting the [Federal Trade Commission](https://www.ftc.gov/) website.

### Security

Visit our Fraud Information Center for additional information about how we protect your personal information and additional measures that you can take to help deter, detect and defend against fraud.

### Updates to our Online Privacy Practices

We may update our Online Privacy Practices as need arises. When updates are made, we will let you know using means deemed appropriate for the changes such as by posting the revising the “Last Updated” date noted on this page.  Any changes to our Online Privacy Practices will become effective when posted unless noted otherwise.
